DALLAN JONES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a full-stack web developer with an extensive background in computers and programming. I am able to build complex back-end applications while maintaining a friendly user experience. I have been studying on my own as well as attending Juno College for front-end development and Brock University for computer science

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell: 905-380-8445 contact@dallan.ca www.dallan.ca www.github.com/dallanj www.twitter.com/dallanjonez www.linkedin.com/in/dallanj Based in Niagara Falls, ON, Canada

EDUCATION

Juno College 2021

- Web Development Immersive Bootcamp
- Con ED JavaScript Course

Brock University 2016-2021

- Computer Science 2 Years
- Business Economics 1 Year

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Gaucho. Server. Line Cook

Hilton Hotel. (2017 - 2021)

- Worked in a variety of roles within a fast-paced environment while adhering to food safety standards and a focus on customer service.
- Assisted customers in an appropriate manner
- Maintained a specific food handling standard within the workplace

Post Harvest Technician

Canopy Growth (2018 - 2019)

- Responsible for handling and maintaining trimming machines (sharpening blades and cleaning individual machine parts)
- Developed and maintained strict cleanliness protocols for workplace sanitization
- Overseen green house plants to maintain a specific standard

TOP PROJECTS

Relay Chat

A secure encrypted live chat platform

- Built using; PHP, SQL, jQuery, PGP software, HTML & CSS
- The backend was built using OOP PHP following an MVC structure $\,$
- Used asynchronous AJAX calls to PHP scripts to manipulate the $\ensuremath{\mathsf{DOM}}$
- Used PGP encryption for messages between users and hashed each user's password within the MySQL database

Sun Run

An app that utilizes Location IQ and Sunrise/Sunset APIs as well as being connected to a firebase database

- Built using React, Firebase, HTML & CSS
- Used multiple APIs and integrated firebase to hold unique user IDs
- Created a sleek and user friendly interface with accessibility
- Worked within a group of students and utilizing Git

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- PHP, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Linux, Networking, Java, Python
- Advanced programming fundamentals
- OOP PHP & React and also following MVC structure
- Utilizing external libraries and frameworks